<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>Hi everyone,

We have closed this thread, and would like to remind you that discussion of sexually suggestive or sexually explicit topics is not appropriate discussion material for the official Rift forums.

If anyone has questions or concerns about this thread closure, please feel free to contact us at community@riftgame.com.

Thank you!</text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>Hi everyone,

We have done some clean-up in this thread and we would like to remind everyone that all areas of these forums support English language only at this time. 

We understand and appreciate that some of our community members are more comfortable writing in their native language, but we ask that you please respect that they support English language only and do not post in other languages, please. This ensures that the Rift Development and Community Teams, and the Rift Community can understand your posts.

Thank you.</text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>ryanr69, thank you for removing the link from your first post. Linking to them on our forums inadvertently advertises for them, and we know that's not what you want!

If you see someone advertising the sale of in-game currency on our forums, please flag the post. If this happens in-game, type /cs or hit the "?" button to report them. If you see a gold selling site for Rift while not on our forums or in-game, please feel free to let us know about it via our Ask a Question page.

Thank you!</text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>Hi everyone,  
This thread was not constructive to begin with and has gone downhill from there, so we've closed it. Please remember to keep your comments respectful and constructive at all times on our forums, even when you disagree with others.   
If anyone has questions or concerns about this thread closure, please feel free to contact us at community@riftgame.com.  
Thank you!
   </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>Hi folks,  
We've closed this thread and would like to take a moment to explain why. If you wish to contact a specific community member (or members), we ask that you please send a private message instead of creating "@ name" threads. This helps us to cut down on the amount of spam on our forums.  
Thank you!
   </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>noteworthy</category>
    <text>Hi, All!  
I've seen a few questions floating around about the servers and I wanted to take a few minutes to get you some answers.  Can you make a characters from both factions on the same server?  
Yes. There are no limits on this.  Is that the whole list of servers?  
This is the Head Start list of servers. More servers of various types will be opened as needed. Watch for announcements here and on Twitter and Facebook as we open them.  Can each shard only hold 1500 players?  
I keep seeing references to a dev saying that each sever would only hold 1500 people. The actual quote was from a very old IRC chat where one of our devs was talking about numbers for that current beta as the servers were opened. We do not release specific numbers about our servers. But we saw higher numbers with each beta and the same thing applies to release. The 1500 rumor is false.    </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>Hi folks,  
We've closed this thread and would like to take a moment to explain why. If you wish to contact a specific community member (or members), we ask that you please send a private message instead of creating "@ name" threads. This helps us to cut down on the amount of spam on our forums.  
Thank you!
   </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>noteworthy</category>
    <text>Redwood City, CA here    </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>Hi everyone,  
We've closed this thread, but we'd like to remind everyone that if you ever have a question or concern about a moderation action, we ask you to please email us at community@riftgame.com. We're always willing to discuss things with you. Also, if you feel we've missed something in a thread, please flag it and we'll look into it. We do our best, but things may slip past us sometimes.  
Thank you!
   </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>Hi folks,  
We've closed this thread and would like to take a moment to explain why. If you wish to contact a specific community member (or members), we ask that you please send a private message instead of creating "@ name" threads. This helps us to cut down on the amount of spam on our forums.  
Thank you!
   </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>Hi folks,  
We've closed this thread and would like to take a moment to explain why. If you wish to contact a specific community member (or members), we ask that you please send a private message instead of creating "@ name" threads. This helps us to cut down on the amount of spam on our forums.  
Thank you!
   </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>service-status</category>
    <text>Seastone, Belmont, Aedraxis, and Spritescar are unlocking now.</text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>service-status</category>
    <text>Servers should be starting back up shortly.</text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>service-status</category>
    <text>This set of four servers is going under for another restart to set it back to normal. Investigation into the root cause of the recent instability is still ongoing. </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>service-status</category>
    <text>Hi all,

Engineers are currently taking a look at the issues occuring on the Seastone, Belmont, Aedraxis, and Spitescar cluster. They're in the process of restarting things now and also investigating the root cause of the repeat server rollovers.

I'll update here as soon as we have more solid information.</text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>moderation</category>
    <text>This thread has been closed per the thread author's request, but recruitment is still active and open. </text>
  </data>
  <data>
    <category>service-status</category>
    <text>The North America region servers will be coming down for a small update at 1:00pm PST. Estimated downtime is ** 30 minutes **.

Included in this update are additional server performance/stability fixes.

More information posted here as I get it!

EDIT: 1:11pm PST
Shards are coming back locked shortly. </text>
  </data>
</root>
